# CURTHBERT CHAWIRA

Computer Engineer



• HARARE, ZIMBABWE

✓ curthbertchawira2016@gmail.com

+263 71 484 2871

### **Profile**

A fully qualified Computer Engineer with experience as IT Support for network, operating systems and applications at the end user level. I am enthusiastic about developing a career in computer Engineering. My ability to stay focussed under pressure allows me to perform efficiently and with precision in high demand situations. I possess excellent analytical and problem-solving skills with the ability to make independent judgements. I strive to be empathetic, respectful and cooperative in all interactions. I am highly numerate and with a solid mathematical scientific background. With а commitment to my personal development and achievement, I endeavour to be resourceful and creative in all my endeavours, bringing a fresh perspective to situations while upholding core company values.

# **Professional Experience**

# **IT Support and Network Administrator,**

Taat Consulting

07/2021 | Harare, Zimbabwe
Information Security and Data Privacy, manage
daily backup jobs. Oversee network security.
Perform intermediate level maintenance and
configuration tasks. Troubleshoot and resolve
network communication issues. Support IT
approved software for desktop and laptop
computers. Configure machines, software,
printers and network access. Primarily worked
alongside a Senior Mentor, which required
maintaining effective communication, ability
to learn quickly in order to adapt to an initially
unfamiliar environment and enhanced my
ability to question and analyze critically.

# **Information Systems Technical / Software Development,** *Pnrhost*

02/2021 – 04/2021 | Harare, Zimbabwe
Software Development. Website using
WordPress. Analyse and resolves service desk
support problems. Provide end user training
and support. Provides with IT systems support
and maintenance on desktops, laptops, server
hardware, work. Infrastructure,
Communication systems and carryout end
user support. Backup of active equipment
configurations and configuration of the backup
equipment.

Web Developer, Gigabyte Ltd

06/2020 - 09/2020 | Nicosia, Cyprus Worked as part of a development team to implement the use of Flutter and dart. Collaborated with the supervisor to successfully debug issues in the GUI for the mobile application. Participated in clientbased projects to design and implement mobile applications using dart and flutter. Collaborated in and participated in designing a UI and implementing the database by migrating a web-based barcode system into a mobile application. Worked as part of a team tasked to design, develop and implement an application for small businesses. Developed project spec questionnaire to identify client needs and streamline the project development

process by writing the software requirements

and the project documentation

### **Skills**

Troubleshooting applications, hardware and software, Network security, Dynamic Web design and Developer, Front end and Backend developer, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, ASP.Net and PHP, SQL, NoSQL, MySQL, and Oracle SQL developer, Software programmer (C++, C, Basic, C#, Linux, Python etc.) Windows Server, Information security. Database Management Systems (SQL, MySQL, Oracle, and XML) Database Security Cisco networking (CCNA routing and switching, security) Software installations on desktop and laptops, Data backup

# **Projects**

**Car rental management,** Web-based online application for managing car for rental. I used html, CSS, JavaScript as frontend designing, PHP and SQL for backend 02/2018 – 06/2018

**Churn predictor,** Predict if customer is going churn or not. I used Python as programming language and also technologies such as Machine Learning
02/2017 – 06/2017

#### **Education**

BSc in Computer Engineering, Bachelor of Computer Sciences in Computer Engineering, European University of Lefke 02/2016 – 06/2021